Prabhjyot Gambhir

Software Engineer

(778)-674-7443 knowprabhjyot@gmail.com https://knowprabhjyot.github.io

Summary

Software Engineer with 4 years of industry experience in developing scalable web applications with an engaging user interface. Specialized in writing clean and modular code and adhered to best practices in the industry. Additionally, a year of experience instructing students and guiding them through fully developed apps.

Industry Experience

IPD Analytics, Hyderabad - Software Engineer. April 2021 - October 2021 (Full time)

- Developed and Delivered **Rebates monitor**, **Clinical pipeline** products for drug and financial insights, later was assigned full ownership.
- Transitioned state management to Redux and Recoil from Context API.
- Provided ongoing maintenance and new features to legacy codebase built with Javascript, React, Node.js, Mongodb.
- Worked in transition from RESTful API architecture to Apollo Federation GraphQL.

Keysight technologies, Gurgaon - R&D Engineer II, February 2018 - April 2021 (Full time)

- Developed whole Front End architecture and implemented different plugin designs for Pathwave Cloud Platform namely – Test Library, Stations Management and Test operations, Switch Manager plugins. Ensured utmost quality design and two different themes.
- Worked in transitioning from Monolith Service architecture to Microservice architecture in collaboration to the team. Additionally developed a library called Alloy for internal use.

Relevant Experience

Vancouver Community College - CST Instructor, September 2022 - PRESENT (Part time)

 Currently teaching courses like Javascript, Typescript, React.js, Node.js, GraphQL, PWA, React Native to international Students.

Cornerstone College, Vancouver - WMAD Instructor, October 2021 - PRESENT (Part time)

 Currently teaching courses like Javascript, Typescript, React.js, Node.js, GraphQL, PWA, React Native to international Students.

Skills

- React.js, React Native, Angular, Node.js, Microservices
- Javascript, Typescript, Java
- HTML, CSS, SASS, Material Design, Bootstrap, JQuery
- Devops AWS, Heroku, Linux, Docker, Kubernetes

Education

Langara College, Vancouver - *Post Degree Diploma in Web and Mobile Development* (May 2021- December 2022) **Guru Gobind Singh University, Delhi-** *Bachelors in Technology , Computer Science* (May 2013- May 2017)